

DATA SCIENTIST · PHD (COMPUTER SCIENCE)

Amsterdam. The Netherlands

publications (Scopus) | ☐ dmitrii-altukhov-258b05233 | ☑ altukhov.dm@gmail.com | ☐ +316 136 36 770

Profile __

I specialize in software engineering and data science with 8-years experience building data analysis algorithms. I'm passionate about programming while having a strong background in applied mathematics.

Skills

Python, Java, C/C++, MATLAB, Git, machine learning, statistics, optimization

Experience _____

SBDA Group Astana, Kazakhstan (remote)

Data scientist, contract Sep. 2023 – Oct. 2023

• Developed and implemented a tool for optimizing manufacturing schedule in **Python**

Artificial Intelligence Research Institute (AIRI)

Moscow, Russia

RESEARCH FELLOW Feb. 2022 – Apr. 2023

- Built deep learning model for decoding speech from MEG data in PyTorch, meg_speech_decoding on github
- Developed real-time pipeline for EEG timeseries analysis using **Python**

Higher School of Economics, Centre for Cognition and Decision Making

Moscow, Russia

RESEARCH FELLOW, PYTHON SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2021

- Led 4-people group developing software for real-time feature extraction and 3D visualization of brain activity from EEG in Python
- Created a pipeline for MEG data preprocessing, see metacognition, MRI_metacognition on github

University of Montreal, CERNEC lab., and Moscow MEG Center

Montreal, Canada, Moscow, Russia

VISITING RESEARCHER, TEMPORARY POSITION

Feb 2015 - Dec 2018

- Built a classifier for ASD patients vs. Controls with 75% accuracy using classical ML and information geometry in Python
- Co-developed an open-source **Python** package for heavy neuroimaging data processing, Neuropycon
- Published four papers in collaboration with the University of Montreal

Scientific Research Institute of System Analysis

Moscow, Russia

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, PROMOTED TO JUNIOR RESEARCH FELLOW

Jun. 2011 - Jan. 2015

 $\bullet \ \ \text{Tested software for simulations of flow in jet engines; implemented a droplet evaporation model in \textbf{C++} \\$

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Moscow, Russia

 $\label{thm:conomics} \mbox{Higher School of Economics, Faculty of Computer Science}$

Jan. 2016 - Nov. 2021

- Thesis: "Optimal methods for functional connectivity estimation in magnetoencephalography."; GPA: 4.0
- Published a paper in a leading neuroscientific journal (see Ossadtchi et al. [2018]) by proposing an algorithm for brain signals analysis.

Specialist degree in Mechanics (Masters equivalent)

Moscow, Russia

LOMONOSOV MOSCOW STATE UNIVERSITY, DEPARTMENT OF MECHANICS AND MATHEMATICS

Sep. 2008 - Jun. 2013

• Thesis: "Enhancement and validation of LOGOS software for simulations of the reactive fluid flows."

Honors & Awards ____

• Selected for 2-year HSE Academic Scholarship for a high-impact publication

Moscow, Russia

2019

St. Petersburg, Russia

201

* Selected 1-st out of 5 teams IEEE Brain Data Bank Challenge for building a BCI drinking game